<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>amandamata</title>
    <link>https://amandamata.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on amandamata</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 06:13:07 -0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amandamata.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Curly braces on new line in vscode</title>
      <link>https://amandamata.github.io/curly-brace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2023 06:13:07 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amandamata.github.io/curly-brace/</guid>
      <description>en pt-pt
This pass week I wake up early every day trying to do only one thing: make Visual Studio Code insert a new line before a curly bracket, braces {}.
I have this:
if (true){ // do something } and I want to format it like this:
if (true) { // do something } Was not as easy thing as may seem. Many sites and stack overflow have the same question, with many disappointing people without a resolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding folders in linux</title>
      <link>https://amandamata.github.io/folders-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 07:55:10 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amandamata.github.io/folders-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>en pt-pt
You&amp;rsquo;ve just installed linux and you&amp;rsquo;re used to the structure of windows and its directories, so you&amp;rsquo;ll take a look in your file manager looking for the disk C: and you can&amp;rsquo;t find it&amp;hellip; Knowing Linux directories can help administer the system and understand how it works.
If we analyze windows and linux, they ended up evolving differently in terms of directory structure. Linux is much more like any other system with unix roots like macOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application of queue</title>
      <link>https://amandamata.github.io/queue/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amandamata.github.io/queue/</guid>
      <description>en pt-pt
What is a queue? A queue is a collection of entities that are maintained in a sequence and can be modified by the addition of entities at one end of the sequence and the removal of entities from the other end of sequence. Wikipedia
Imagine that we have a user&amp;rsquo;s API.
We can create users in the system and then retrieve them back, maybe update and maybe delete them, send an email to the user, and also make a request to another API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://amandamata.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amandamata.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>en pt-pt
Me Hi! My name is Amanda, I&amp;rsquo;m 27 years old.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with technology since 2014 and with programming since 2019.
Welcome to my corner of the internet.
Come on in and make yourself at home.
My blog is a loose collection of things learned. Work I’m a Software Engineer at PagarMe.
I&amp;rsquo;m graduated in Computer Science (but we all know the learning never ends). Contact Wanna get in touch?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
